<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-12-24T15:42:25-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Bryan’s Digital Garden</title><subtitle>A place for the thoughts, designs, writing, and code of Bryan Sebesta</subtitle><author><name>Bryan Sebesta</name></author><entry><title type="html">Piranesi Review</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/12/23/piranesi-review.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Piranesi Review" /><published>2020-12-23T17:00:26-07:00</published><updated>2020-12-23T17:00:26-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/12/23/piranesi-review</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/12/23/piranesi-review.html">&lt;p&gt;Piranesi is an enchanting Book, filled with Wonder. I felt like a child reading It, and I wish It didn’t have to end. The House was a surprising character.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Bryan Sebesta</name></author><summary type="html">Piranesi is an enchanting Book, filled with Wonder. I felt like a child reading It, and I wish It didn’t have to end. The House was a surprising character.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Discipleship as the End of the World</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/faith/2020/12/20/discipleship-as-the-end-of-the-world.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Discipleship as the End of the World" /><published>2020-12-20T17:00:26-07:00</published><updated>2020-12-20T17:00:26-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/faith/2020/12/20/discipleship-as-the-end-of-the-world</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/faith/2020/12/20/discipleship-as-the-end-of-the-world.html">&lt;p&gt;Adam Miller has a very distinctive style when he writes. It’s lucid and electric, a welcome combination given would be an obscure and dry subject: theology. In his recent volume &lt;em&gt;Mormon: A Brief Theological Introduction&lt;/em&gt;, he’s written:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Imagine, on the one hand, a certain kind of religion. Imagine a religion that required you to lose your life to save it (cf. Matthew 10:39). Imagine a religion whose introductory ritual required you to symbolically die, be buried, and then rise from the grave, committed now to living what remained of your life as something that belonged not to you but to God—bearing his name, filled with his Spirit, acting as his agent (cf. Romans 6:3–7). Imagine a religion that might, at any time, ask you, as Jesus did the rich young man, to “sell all that thou hast, and distribute unto the poor” (Luke 18:22). Imagine a religion premised on the necessity of sacrificing all things, a religion that claimed up front, as the Lectures on Faith do, that any “religion that does not require the sacrifice of all things, never has power sufficient to produce the faith necessary unto life and salvation” (Lectures on Faith, 6:7). Or imagine, finally, a religion that explicitly required you to return to God, by way of consecration, all of your time, talents, and possessions. Can you imagine this sort of religion? Can you imagine a religion that required the sacrifice of all things?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Now imagine, on the other hand, a certain kind of world. Imagine a world structured by time and pinned to its relentless flow. Imagine a world where everything that arises will also pass away, a world where, as Joseph Smith claimed, “as the Lord liveth, if it had a beginning, it will have an end.”2 Imagine a world where possessions decay, buildings crumble, triumphs fade, governments collapse, continents drift, and mass extinctions happen again and again. Imagine a world where children grow up and leave home, where people get sick and grow old, where everyone dies. Imagine a world where the people you love—for as long as they live, for better or worse—are constantly changing. In this kind of world, people are more like rivers than rocks. They persist but never stay the same. Imagine this kind of marriage, this kind of family, this kind of home. This isn’t hard to do. My grandparents are dead. My father can no longer walk. The young man my wife married is gone forever. Our daughter is already grown and the five-year-old girl I held in my lap is never coming back. The sixteen-year-old girl I took to the movies is never coming back. Does this perpetual passing away hurt? Shouldn’t it? Resurrection doesn’t solve this problem. Immortality doesn’t solve this problem. Resurrection doesn’t freeze the world in place, trapping us in a block of ice-cold perfection. Resurrection is the promise that, in Christ, life can continue to pass, not that it will finally stop passing. Imagine, then, a world where you are guaranteed to lose everything and everyone. Imagine a world where it is always possible to care for things but never possible to keep them. Now, to press home the urgent, contemporary reality of such a world—and, perhaps, the urgent contemporary relevance of the Book of Mormon—take what we’ve imagined thus far and push it a step farther. Imagine that these are actually the latter days. Imagine that the world itself is going to end, that “the earth shall be rolled together as a scroll, and the elements shall melt with fervent heat” (Mormon 9:2). Imagine a world that could end tomorrow in nuclear winter, in a cloudburst of ballistic missiles and blast radii and poisonous fallout. Or imagine one single bomb that, all by itself, would be powerful enough to ruin the world and render it uninhabitable. Imagine that bomb going off instantaneously. Now imagine that bomb’s detonation requiring a five-minute count-down, a twenty-four-hour countdown, a monthlong countdown, a yearlong countdown. Imagine, even, a world-ending bomb with a fuse the length of an average human life—when the baby is born, the fuse is lit—a fuse long enough for there “to be great doubtings and disputations among the people, notwithstanding so many signs had been given” (3 Nephi 8:4). Regardless of how the world ends, we can rest assured that it is going to end. And regardless of how we lose everything and everyone we love, we will lose them—if only by the most quiet, familiar, and local means. Slowly and singly or swiftly and collectively, death will claim every one of us. “A person’s life is like grass. Like a flower in the field it flourishes, but when the hot wind blows, it disappears, and one can no longer even spot the place where it once grew” (Psalms 103:15–16, NET). Time will dispossess us all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is electric, and I love it.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Bryan Sebesta</name></author><category term="Faith" /><category term="book of mormon" /><category term="lds" /><summary type="html">Adam Miller has a very distinctive style when he writes. It’s lucid and electric, a welcome combination given would be an obscure and dry subject: theology. In his recent volume Mormon: A Brief Theological Introduction, he’s written:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Image Test</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/12/19/image-test.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Image Test" /><published>2020-12-19T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-12-19T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/12/19/image-test</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/12/19/image-test.html">&lt;p&gt;This is a test.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://digital-garden.s3-us-west-1.amazonaws.com/7a8cd639-3111-45d2-81d9-53ca4d749fa5-screen-shot-2020-12-16-at-83903-am.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Bryan</name></author><summary type="html">This is a test.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">From Systematic Planners to Long-term Improvisers</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/12/15/from-systematic-planners-to-long-term-improvisers.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="From Systematic Planners to Long-term Improvisers" /><published>2020-12-15T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-12-15T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/12/15/from-systematic-planners-to-long-term-improvisers</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/12/15/from-systematic-planners-to-long-term-improvisers.html">&lt;p&gt;My brother recently asked me when I thought I’d buy a house. Not only was I incapable of formulating a good answer–I really &lt;em&gt;don’t&lt;/em&gt; know–but I also struggled to come up with good criteria for answering the question. Buying a house is a major commitment to a &lt;em&gt;place&lt;/em&gt;, and it depends on things in life (especially my job prospects) &lt;em&gt;settling&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But in many ways, this year has been &lt;em&gt;unsettling&lt;/em&gt;: I started in New York City, and then the pandemic hit. I lived several months with my parents in California, and have now “settled” in Utah, living near family here. But I’m still not sure what’s coming next. I still have my job, but it could change in an instant, as it has for many of my friends. And if so, am I entirely sure I want to continue doing what I’m doing in my career? Much as I like Utah, do I want to spend many more years here? Will family stay? And what, of course, will happen with the pandemic? Will things be fixed soon? Will my work reopen in New York City, or will we work remotely forever?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other words, it feels so hard to make long-terms plans. To form a strategy. I was feeling bad about this, but then I read Alan Jacobs’ new essay called &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thenewatlantis.com/publications/from-tech-critique-to-ways-of-living&quot;&gt;From Tech Critique to Ways of Living&lt;/a&gt;, and in it he makes this point:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We might think of the shifting relationship of human beings to the natural world in the terms offered by German sociologist Gerd-Günter Voß, who has traced our movement through three different models of the “conduct of life.” The first, and for much of human history the only conduct of life, is what he calls the &lt;em&gt;traditional&lt;/em&gt;. Your actions within the traditional conduct of life proceed from social and familial circumstances, from what is thus handed down to you. In such a world it is reasonable for family names to be associated with trades, trades that will be passed down from father to son: Smith, Carpenter, Miller. But the rise of the various forces that we call “modernity” led to the emergence of the &lt;em&gt;strategic&lt;/em&gt; conduct of life: a life with a plan, with certain goals — to get into law school, to become a cosmetologist, to get a corner office.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Quite recently, thanks largely to totalizing technology’s formation of a world in which, to borrow a phrase from Marx and Engels, “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.marxists.org/archive/marx/works/1848/communist-manifesto/ch01.htm&quot;&gt;all that is solid melts into air&lt;/a&gt;,” the strategic model of conduct is replaced by the &lt;em&gt;situational&lt;/em&gt;. Instead of being systematic planners, we become agile improvisers: If the job market is bad for your college major, you turn a side hustle into a business. But because you know that your business may get disrupted by the tech industry, you don’t bother thinking long-term; your current gig might disappear at any time, but another will surely present itself, which you will assess upon its arrival.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This helped bring clarity to my question. I, and many of my friends, am being forced away from the &lt;em&gt;strategic&lt;/em&gt; conduct of life–a life with a plan–to become agile improvisers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I think that–&lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; sense, that this could change anytime, and so long-term planning becomes less useful–is what makes answering my brothers’s question hard. I don’t know when I’ll buy a house, or even if I’ll &lt;em&gt;ever&lt;/em&gt; buy a house. (#rentForLife) Being an agile improviser is really important these days, and I accept that. There are perks, too, that can come with that: being resilient in a fast-paced world, being adaptable, capable of learning new skills. But I know I &lt;em&gt;want&lt;/em&gt; to find somewhere I can settle in, eventually: a place to call home, a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dkolb.org/sprawlingplaces/generalo/complexi/thickver.html&quot;&gt;thick place&lt;/a&gt; that I can belong to.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Bryan</name></author><summary type="html">My brother recently asked me when I thought I’d buy a house. Not only was I incapable of formulating a good answer–I really don’t know–but I also struggled to come up with good criteria for answering the question. Buying a house is a major commitment to a place, and it depends on things in life (especially my job prospects) settling.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My First Try with Jekyll</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/11/27/my-first-try-with-jekyll.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My First Try with Jekyll" /><published>2020-11-27T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-11-27T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/11/27/my-first-try-with-jekyll</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/11/27/my-first-try-with-jekyll.html">&lt;p&gt;Well, I’m a developer now. That’s how it works, no? You find yourself enmeshed in terms like “CI” and “Git” and “Liquid programming” and “Statically generated website,” and suddenly—like magic—you’re a developer!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s how it feels, anyway. And it’s fun. In my high school days, I used to stay after for long hours, programming a website. I haven’t pulled the long “developer hours” in years, and now that I am, I ask myself: why not? It’s so much fun.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Bryan</name></author><category term="web-development" /><category term="jekyll" /><summary type="html">Well, I’m a developer now. That’s how it works, no? You find yourself enmeshed in terms like “CI” and “Git” and “Liquid programming” and “Statically generated website,” and suddenly—like magic—you’re a developer!</summary></entry></feed>